Akash Sampurnanand Pandey

SUMMARY

asp
9085@nyu.edu | +1-(929)-498-6395 | Linkedin | Git Hub

A seasoned Software Engineering workhorse with a Master's in Computer Science from New York University and around 2 years of professional experience in public companies (Amazon and Capgemini), a Series D startup (Forward Health), and a seed-funded startup (Acadza). Skilled in Back-end technologies using Go, Python (Django), and Javascript(Node.js), and Front-end technologies like React.js. Portfolio Website

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, Go, JavaScript, Java, SQL, C++, HTML, CSS.

Development Frameworks: Frontend: React.js, Flask. Backend: Protobuf, gRPC, Django, Node.js.

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, PostgreSQL

Technology and Tools: REST APIs, Postman, AWS, Microservices, Git, Visual Studio Code, Linux, IntelliJ.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Forward Health, San Francisco as Software Engineer

Feb 2023 - June 2023

- Created 5 new APIs end to end using Go for targeted App deployment using gRPC and Protobuff. This service is being used by over 40,000 Forward users.
- Changed the build from Travis CI to GitHub Actions reducing CI/CD pipeline build by 50 percent.
- Managed and modified an E2E API for Health Apps Service use widely across the company.
- Worked with AWS stack and cloudformation along with logging services like Honeycomb.
 Skills developed GoLang, ProtoBuff, GRPC, Backend, Microservices, Agile, TDD, Git, AWS

Amazon Web Services (AWS), Seattle as Software Developer Intern

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- Created and optimized the MetricMath Rule as part of the Health Guardian platform in AWS Lambda Team to enhance Rule integration for a microservice used by AWS Lambda customers.
- Detected Service Outage and simulated production environment to aid the Amazon Science team to finetune Detection Algorithms.
- Worked in a Test Driven Development (TDD) environment writing unit tests with 95 percent plus coverage along with Integration tests. Skills developed Java, Backend, Microservices, Agile, TDD, Git

Acadza Technologies as Chief Product Officer

Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

- Started ground up with the founder at the early stage Ed-Tech startup and managed a team of 25 people across departments. Product Link.
- Delivered Django Content Management System product. Skills developed Python, Django, Agile, Project Management, Full Stack Web Development, Git

Capgemini as Associate (Software Engineering) Consultant

2016 - 2017

- Worked on a commercial technology platform widely used in Health Insurance Industry called Guidewire, using AGILE SDLC.
- Created REST APIs and Relational Data models to implement business logic. Skills developed Python, Django, Agile, Project Management, Full Stack Web Development, Git

EDUCATION

New York University, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

Master of Science (M.S.) in Computer Science, GPA: 3.6/4.0

Indian Institute of Technology - Varanasi, India

Jul 2012 - May 2016

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) in Engineering, GPA: 7.51/10

PUBLICATIONS

Automated Bayesian Hyperparameter Tuning of ML Classifiers addressing Customer Relationship Management (CRM): First Author. Link to Publication in Springer.